My father...
我爹
He just sent me away.
他干脆把我送走了
You're not alone.
你不孤单的
What you've lost
过去失去的
will come back to you.
未来会全部拥有回来的
When I first got back home,
刚回来的时候
I complained a lot.
怨气很多
But gradually,
但是渐渐地
I calmed down.
心平气和多了
I often think of
我常常想起
what you instructed me on the first day of class.
你第一天上课训导我的话
You asked me to think about
你让我好好想想
how to make contributions
身为男儿
as a grown man.
该如何立世
I'm no longer a child,
我已经不是一个孩子
but a grown man.
我是个男人
I shouldn't be stuck in old injustices.
我不该执念于过去的不公
Instead, I should focus on the future
应该放眼于未来
and take on responsibilities
承担起自己的责任
to protect my family.
守护起这个家
Jiashang,
嘉上
you want to protect your family.
你要守护的这个家
But I have to destroy it.
我却要毁灭它
One day,
终有一天
we'll be irreconcilable opposites
我们会注定站在不可交融的对立面
and even have to fight desperately.
甚至 不死不休
Thank you, Jiashang.
谢谢你 嘉上
You saved my life.
是你救了我
I didn't do anything.
我并没有做什么
He just let go of you.
是他放开了你
You made him let go of me.
是你让他放开我的
You scared him
你让他恐惧
so that he didn't dare to hurt me.
他才不敢伤害我
Miss Feng.
先生
Luckily, I still have you.
幸好还有你
Mr. Jiashang,
少爷
something is wrong.
出事了
Go check it out.
你快去吧
Miss Feng,
先生
go with me.
你同我一起去吧
I...
我
What happened?
怎么回事啊
This man was bringing the meal to Guo Dazhuang.
这小子给郭大壮送饭
There was a marinated egg in it.
饭里面有一颗卤蛋
He was gluttonous
他看见了嘴馋
and ate the egg.
就把那颗卤蛋给吃了
Then he was poisoned to death.
结果就中毒死了
Where did he get the meal?
这饭是从哪里送来的
From the small kitchen.
小厨房
I've had the kitchen besieged.
我已经安排人把厨房给包围了
Everyone in the kitchen swore
厨房上下的人都发誓
that they only prepared a bowl of rice
他们只安排了一碗米饭
and a plate of greens
和一盘青菜
and no one prepared the egg.
根本就没有放过那颗卤蛋
Now this man is dead.
现在这小子又死了
We don't know where he got the egg.
都不知道这颗卤蛋从哪儿来的
Take him away
带下去
and bury him.
好生安葬
Yes.
是
Your old boss
你的老东家
is quite considerate.
真是重情重义
To make sure you would die,
怕你走得不利索
he prepared severe toxins for you.
还特地给你下了重毒
Mr. Jia... Mr. Jiashang...
大大
I... I... I...
我 我 我
I'm desperately regretting it.
我真的把肠子都悔青了我
Mr. Jiashang, I beg you.
大少爷 我求求你了
I beg you. Please save my life.
求求你了 你就救我一命吧
I'll be your loyal servant, Mr. Jiashang.
我会给你做牛做马 大少爷
I'll tell you anything...
俺把俺知道的
Anything I know.
全 全告诉你
Looks like a dead man threatens better than a bullet.
看来死人比子弹管用啊
Tell me about it.
说说吧
Think carefully before you start.
这回想清楚再说
Don't miss anything again.
可别再遗漏什么了
I'm indeed paid
俺确实收了钱
to transmit intel to outsiders.
给外人传递情报
But we do specific jobs.
但是俺们都有分工
We've never seen each other.
平时也没有什么交集
I only transmit the intel.
俺就是一个传递情报的
As for what happens out of here,
出去之后
I...
俺
I know nothing about it.
俺啥也不知道啊
Mr. Jiashang,
大少爷
I do this because I'm in gambling debt.
俺是因为欠了点赌债
And my mother is sick.
俺娘还生着病呢
Get to the point!
说重点
How do you usually get the intel?
你是怎么取情报的
My superior says
上头人说
there's an old locust tree beside the pavilion
在亭子旁边有一棵老槐树
and there's a hole in it.
树上有个树洞
I'm asked
他们让俺
to check the hole every two days.
每两天去一次
Once there's a note in it,
只要一有情报
I deliver it.
就给送出来
Where to deliver it?
送去哪里啊
The Foundling Home at the east street corner.
送到
I'm asked
他们让俺
to put the note in an old newspaper
把情报放在旧报纸里面
and then
然后
throw it...
把它丢在
Throw it...
丢在
In the drum
丢在门厅外
outside the hall.
门厅外的转桶里
They usually pay me
他 他们给俺钱的时候
in the middle of the night
都是大半夜
when I can't see anyone clearly.
俺 俺连个人的影子都见不着
When was the last time you delivered a note?
你最后一次传递情报是什么时候
It was...
就是
Right. Right.
对对
the day after the Mid-Autumn Festival.
中秋节的第二天
Early that morning,
那天一大早
I saw a note in the hole
俺就看见树洞里面有情报
and then I delivered it.
俺就给送出去了
What's on the note?
上面写的什么
I stole a glance at it.
俺当时偷偷看了一眼
It was a piece of blank paper.
那就是一张白纸
Not even a single word was on it.
上面一个字都没有
Blank paper?
白纸
Don't you know who wrote the note?
你难道不知道你在跟谁传递情报吗
I... I...
俺 俺这个人
I'm not very clever.
不大聪明
But I'm aware
但是俺知道
that the more I know,
有些事情
the bigger trouble I'll be in.
麻烦就越大
Have you contacted Miss Sun
你和西堂的孙小姐
of West Hall?
有过接触吗
Miss Sun?
孙小姐
She...
她
When she read books in the garden,
花园里看书的时候
I looked at her from behind.
俺就远远地看个背影
I didn't even see her face.
连个模样都没看出来
Are you sure?
你确定
Yes. Yes.
确 确定
Mr. Jia... Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷 我 我对天发誓
that what I'm saying is true.
我说的都是真的
The old locust tree beside the octagonal pavilion?
是八角亭边的那棵老槐树吗
Yes, yes.
对对
That's it.
就是那儿
At...
那个
At eye level,
树上一人高的地方
there's a hole as big as a fist.
有一个拳头大的树洞
How long have you been transmitting the intel?
你这样传情报有多久了
It was last April
俺是去年四月份
that they bought me over.
被他们收买的
Nothing happened
中 中间一直没有什么动静
until this Mid-Autumn Festival.
也就中秋节这次
Mr. Jia... Mr. Jiashang.
大 大少爷
I swear to God.
俺对天发誓
I only did it this once.
真的就这一次
Miss Feng,
先生
how do you think I should punish him?
你觉得我该怎么处置他
He betrayed his master.
背叛东家
He should be severely punished.
理应严惩吧
If you say so,
既然先生都这么说了
take him away.
那就拖下去吧
Mr. Jia... Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷
I kidnapped Miss Feng
我 我劫持冯先生
in a fit of anxiety.
我是一时心急
I'm sorry, Mr. Jiashang.
我混蛋 大少爷
Miss Feng,
冯先生
you're the bigger person.
你大人有大量
Please... Please spare my life.
你就饶俺一命 饶俺一命
Actually,
其实
we can make use of him.
我们可以反利用他一次
Excuse me?
什么
Someone bought him over
有人利用他
to get the intel of your family.
到容家来打探情报
You can also let him
那你也可以让他帮你
get their intel for you.
去打探对方的消息
Have a long-term plan
放长线
to get something bigger.
钓大鱼
Isn't it a better solution?
岂不是一举两得
Right, right.
对对对
I can do that.
可以的
Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷
Mr. Jiashang. Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷 大少爷
I remember that man's voice.
我记得那个人的声音
What have you got?
情况如何
Two servants have the problem of corruption and theft.
有两个贪污偷窃
The other servants are clean.
剩下的没什么大问题
What have you got, then?
你那边审得怎么样了
He confessed.
都招了
He has been hiding in our family
说是在家里
for nearly two years
埋伏了快两年
and he has only transmitted one note recently.
只在最近一次传递过情报
What's on the note?
具体传递了一些什么东西
He has no idea
他就是个跑腿的
because he's only a messenger.
说不出个所以然来
Looks like the spy is indeed in this residence.
看来问题果然出现在府上
Very well.
不过也好
We can take the chance
趁这个机会
to clean out the servants.
将家中的下人全部清理一遍
I'll seriously interrogate
凡是有嫌疑的
all suspected servants.
我都会再仔细审一遍
The delivery address of that batch was written in cipher.
那批货的交货地址是一串密文
Who wrote the ciphertext?
是谁编写的
Mr. Zhao takes charge of ciphers.
密钥平时都是掌握在赵爷手里
There are different codebooks for different batches.
每一批货都有不同的密码本
The storage location of this batch changed.
这批货中途换过存货地点
So, the ciphertext changed, too.
所以密钥也随之更改
I received the telegram.
我接到电报
After that,
接到电报之后
I wrote the ciphertext on the paper.
我将密文写在纸上
After I decoded it,
翻译出来后
I burned the paper.
我就把纸烧掉了
Paper?
纸
It's a little trick.
一点小伎俩而已
We should figure out
我们该注意的是
who managed to sneak into my father's private study
是谁能不留痕迹地
without leaving a trace.
潜入我爹的小书房
It was negligent of me.
是我疏忽了
A spy from within is hard to guard against.
只是家贼难防啊
Jiashang, be more careful, too.
嘉上以后你也要多留心啊
As for Miss Feng,
关于冯先生
let me say something unpleasant.
容我说几句讨人嫌的话
It's not that long ago that you met her.
毕竟你们认识不久
She's an outsider, after all.
她终究是个外人
Even if she doesn't mean to hurt you,
就算她无心害你
someone may use her
也防不住别人利用她
to trap you.
来对付你
She's just a woman.
她也不过是个女人罢了
But you adore her.
可你喜欢她
Then she's a weapon that can hurt you.
她就成了可以伤害你的武器
No wonder girls like you, Xiucheng.
难怪表哥这么招女孩子喜欢
There's a reason for it.
不是没有道理啊
How will you deal with Guo Dazhuang?
那姓郭的你打算怎么处理
I'll make the best use of him
物尽其用
and see if I can track down
看看能不能顺藤摸瓜
the man behind him.
找出背后的人
Fine.
那好
I'll take my leave, then.
我先走了
As for this report...
这份报告
Give it to your father later.
晚点你交给表姨父吧
All right.
好
See you.
不送
Boss,
七爷
something's wrong.
有情况
What's wrong?
怎么了
The Foundling Home called,
育婴堂那边打来电话
saying that some strangers
说有几个生面孔
followed Guo Dazhuang into the hall.
盯着郭大壮进了门厅
They seem to be sent by the Rong Family.
怀疑是容家派来的
I'm afraid
看来郭大壮
Guo Dazhuang's cover was blown.
怕是暴露了
Will Miss Feng be in trouble?
那冯小姐不会有事吧
Rong Jiashang
容嘉上
only tracked down to the Foundling Home.
只查到育婴堂这条线索
It means
说明
they only made Guo Dazhuang confess.
他们只撬开了郭大壮的嘴
Guo Dazhuang and Feng Shizhen
郭大壮跟冯世真
don't know each other's identities.
他们并不知道彼此的身份
By now,
所以到目前为止
Shizhen is safe.
世真是安全的
Then...
那
Do I need to sneak in and check on her?
用不用我潜进去探一探
No.
不用去了
Rong's Residence
现在容家上下
must be heavily guarded.
肯定是戒备森严
If you sneak in,
你要去的话
you'll be caught.
只会自投罗网
Instead of helping Shizhen,
不但帮不了世真
you'll only cause her trouble.
而且还会给她添麻烦
But I believe in one thing.
不过有一点我相信
Shizhen...
世真
I trained her myself.
她是我一手带出来的
I have confidence in her abilities.
我相信她的能力
You're right, Boss.
七爷说的是
How do we deal with Guo Dazhuang?
那郭大壮怎么处理呢
It's dangerous
现在郭大壮在容嘉上手上
when Guo Dazhuang is in the hand of Rong Jiashang.
肯定是不安全的
Try to get him out.
找人把他给我弄出来
What about the Foundling Home?
那育婴堂咱们
Cut it off completely.
这条线彻底切断
It can no longer be used.
不要再用了
Besides,
另外
tell your men
通知你手下的人
to keep a close eye.
给我盯紧了
If anything happens,
有任何风吹草动
let me know.
随时告诉我
Yes.
是
Off you go.
去吧
Go check over there.
你去看那边
No one is in.
没人
Miss Feng.
先生
Did you have a good sleep last night?
昨晚睡得好吗
Yes.
挺好的
How's it going with Guo Dazhuang?
郭大壮那边查得怎么样了
He was rescued.
被救走了
The man behind him is quite powerful.
他背后的人真是厉害
How come?
怎么会这样
Your men were following him, weren't they?
不是一直派人盯着的吗
Miss Feng,
先生
think about it.
你说
In such a big residence,
这么大个公馆
there are so many people.
这么多的人
But how many of them are honest?
真心的能有几个
Miss Feng,
先生
do you trust me?
你相信我吗
I do, of course.
当然了
Then,
那先生
can I trust you?
我能相信你吗
What?
怎么
You don't trust me?
你不信我
I do.
我信
We found out two servants who stole things
查出来两个小偷小摸的
and they have been fired.
已经辞退了
Most of the servants
家里大部分的家仆
are clean,
都没有什么问题
except a gardener.
除了一个园丁
He confessed
他交代
that someone transmitted a message
馆里曾有人通过他
through him.
向外面传递过信息
Have you figured out the person?
查出来是谁了吗
Not yet.
还没有
They transmitted the message through the locust tree in the garden
他们只通过花园里的老槐树来联系
and they didn't see each other.
彼此并没有见过面
However,
只不过
Miss Sun used to like reading under the locust tree.
孙小姐确实喜欢在老槐树下看书
What about those people out there?
外面的人呢
I sent Guo Dazhuang to contact them.
我派郭大壮前去接触了
But he was rescued from the Foundling Home.
结果郭大壮在育婴堂被人救走了
I checked the Foundling Home with my men.
我带人
A foreigner runs it.
是一个洋人开设的
It's clean.
没有什么问题
But its staff composition is quite complicated.
只是它下面的人员构成复杂
So now,
所以暂时
we're not sure who is behind this.
不能确定是何人所为
Someone from the Huang Family
黄家好像有人
works in the Foundling Home.
在育婴堂那边做工
Have the servants replaced if necessary.
把该换的人都换了
Keep a close eye on the Huang Family.
派人盯紧黄家
Once you find out anyone suspicious,
一旦发现什么问题
get him back.
马上给我抓回来
Yes.
是
Things aren't going well with Zhao, either.
老赵那边情况也不太好
He has been tracking down the goods.
追查了这么几日
Looks like
看来
he can hardly get them back.
追回来的可能性很小了
Can you think of any solutions?
你有什么对策吗
I read the freight agreement
我看了运货协议
and did some checking.
也查了一些关于他的情况
I realize
我发现
that Commander Cao
这位曹大帅
pays special attention to this batch of goods.
似乎格外看重这批货
Besides,
而且
the goods aren't delivered
交接这批货的欧洲码头
to the European wharf that we usually use.
也不是我们惯用的那个
Commander Cao and the European buyer aren't trading silver coins,
那是因为曹大帅和欧洲买家交易的
but munitions.
并非现银而是军火
So,
所以
they pick a special wharf for the delivery.
找了一个特殊的码头进行交接
I see.
原来如此
Any ideas?
你有什么想法吗
I think
我想
we can prepare equivalent munitions
我们可以准备等价的军火
as compensation.
来进行赔偿
Be specific.
怎么讲
I read about an item
我看过
in the agreement with Commander Cao.
与曹大帅签订的协议里有一则
If the deal fails
如果是因为我方原因
due to our fault,
导致的交易失败
we need to pay ten times for the loss.
则需要赔偿对方十倍的损失
Ten times the silver coins
十倍的现银
or equivalent munitions.
和等价的军火
Which do you think is better?
您觉得哪一样合算
But at such a critical moment,
只是现在这个节骨眼上
all forces are striving for munitions.
各方势力都在争抢军火
Who can help with our emergency?
谁会有多余的提供给我们救急呢
Where there's a will, there is a way.
事在人为
The canteen I visited has great steak.
之前我去的那家牛排特别好吃
It does?
是吗
Shall I take you there when there's a chance?
有机会可以带你一起去呀
Good idea.
好啊
Yunchi.
云驰
I have something to tell you.
我找你有事
Come over.
过来一下
All right.
好
Excuse me.
失陪一下
Yunchi,
云驰
I know you're well-connected
我知道你在上海滩
and well-informed in Shanghai.
人脉广 消息灵通
I'll count on you to take care of this.
这件事情就交给你了
Will you really listen to your father
你真的要听你爹的话
and take care of the problem for him?
替他摆平此事
You always hate such business, don't you?
你素来不是最讨厌这些铜臭生意吗
He's my father, after all.
他毕竟是我爹
He supports the whole family.
他撑起了整个容家
I can be unruly.
我可以叛逆不羁
I can be cynical, too.
也可以愤世嫉俗
But this is a different case.
但是这次不一样
I get it.
我明白了
You can count on me.
包在我身上
Aunt.
表姨
Aunt, have some tea.
表姨 您喝口茶
You still remember I'm your aunt?
你还知道我是你表姨呀
I took a trip to Hangzhou
我就去了趟杭州
and look what you've done at home.
你可倒好
You ransacked the whole residence.
你们把整个家翻了个底朝天
No, no.
您言重了
That was just a routine inspection
只不过是例行检查
and the sticky-fingered servants were replaced.
把手脚不干净的下人给换了而已
Then why did you only replace
那为什么单单
the servants from my maternal family?
只换了我黄家的人啊
Are you saying
那你的意思是说
that my servants are sticky-fingered?
我的人手脚都不干净了
Are you?
是吗
Here.
这些呢
They confessed
可都是他们自己
and signed it.
签了字承认的
Look.
您看
The assistant accountant
二账房
embezzled over a hundred silver dollars.
拿了咱们家一百多块大洋
This is the manager of the kitchen.
这个是厨房管事
He embezzled the most money.
他贪的是最多的
And this...
还有这个
Look.
您看
Your maid Ms. Liu.
您的贴身佣人
She sold your pearl necklaces.
刘妈拿着您的珍珠项链往外卖
How ungrateful they are!
这几个吃里扒外的东西
Most importantly,
最 最关键的是
Uncle is very upset.
表姨父特别不高兴
He's upset?
他不高兴
Ask him to think about it.
他也不想想
Without my Huang family,
要是没有我们黄家
he wouldn't have been so rich!
他容定坤有今天啊
He must be grateful.
任何时候都要讲良心的
It makes sense
他就算养我们黄家一辈子
even if he supports my family all his life.
那也是应该的
That's not right, Ma'am.
太太此言差矣
Now that you're my father's wife,
太太嫁入容家
you're one of the Rong Family.
那就是容家的人
You should give priority to our benefits.
当然要把容家的利益放在首位
You can help your Huang family.
帮衬娘家不是不可以
But you can't go too far.
但是要有个度
Your family helped my father build up the family fortune.
黄家的确帮我爹发了家
But we have never mistreated them.
但是我们容家也没有亏待过他们
The money we give them every year can even afford an army.
每年给的钱都可以养一支军队了
Your brother was just so greedy.
是黄家舅舅自己贪心不足
He has a no-show job,
坐吃空饷
but he still gets bribery.
还贪污受贿
Now, he's even involved in the spy case.
现在还弄出了刺探机密这种事情
This spy
那个奸细
was recommended by your family.
就是走黄家的门路进来的
Ma'am,
太太
we support those who helped us,
我们容家养恩人
but we never raise those who betrayed us.
但是不养会背叛的人
Wasn't that man recommended by the Sun Family?
不是说是孙家吗
Why is it my family?
这怎么又成了我们黄家
Ma'am, think twice before you talk.
太太说话之前请先想清楚
Are you one of the Rong Family
你到底是容家人
or the Huang Family?
还是黄家人
Who do you think you are?
你是什么东西啊
You know what?
我告诉你哦
You're just a jinx.
你就是个扫把星
A total jinx.
是个克星
Because of you, your mother died.
你先克死了你生母
Then, your little brother died.
然后又克死了你弟弟
Now you even want to hurt me?
你现在连我都不放过啊
I think
我看你啊
you'll also be betrayed
将来也是众叛亲离
and end up all alone.
孤独终老的
You'll die a terrible death.
会不得好死的
Aunt, you're going too far.
表姨 这话太过了
Did I say anything wrong?
我哪说错了
If it weren't for him,
要不是他
my son...
我的辛儿
He wouldn't have been kidnapped!
他怎么会被绑架
He wouldn't have been dead!
怎么会死
He left my son in danger!
是他见死不救
To protect yourself,
你为了保全你自己
you watched those men
你眼睁睁地看着那些人
kill your little brother.
把你的弟弟给害死
Look at you.
你看看你这副德行
You're just as heartless
你跟你爹一样
as your father!
薄情寡义
Aunt. Aunt. Aunt.
表姨 表姨 表姨
You never care for your family!
你们眼里根本就没有什么亲情骨肉
You care for no one, but yourself!
眼里只有你自己
Ma'am, you're being too emotional.
太太现在情绪太激动
I won't talk to you until you calm down.
等你冷静了我再和你说
Rong Jiashang!
容嘉上
Aunt... Aunt...
表 表姨
- Now, your father is still alive. - Aunt. Aunt.
现在你爹还活着
But you are already
你就不把我这个后妈
disrespecting your stepmother?
放在眼里了是吗
You're overthinking, Aunt.
你想太多了表姨
When your father passes away,
等你爹一闭眼
will you kick me out immediately?
你是不是第一个把我赶出门去啊
Aunt, he's leaving.
表姨 人都走了
- You own me my son's life! - Aunt.
你欠我一条人命
Give my son back to me!
你还我辛儿
Why do you think you can swagger before me?
你凭什么对我耀武扬威的
How miserable I am!
我真是作孽
I have a husband.
嫁了一个丈夫
But he's so ungrateful.
狼心狗肺
I had a son.
生了个儿子
But...
那么
But he died when he was so little.
那么小就走了
I hear Mr. Yang has come again.
听说今天杨先生又来了
He seems to have some questions for you.
好像是有什么话要问大家
Do you
你们是
have something to tell Mr. Jiashang?
有话想要跟大少爷说吗
- No.
没有 没有
Get to your business, then.
快去忙吧
Miss Feng, excuse us.
冯先生那我们先走了
- Excuse us.
那我们先走了
Jiashang,
嘉上
I don't want to disturb you.
我不想打扰你
But if...
但是如果
If you want to talk to someone,
你需要有人说说话
I'm right here.
我就在门口
Jiashang.
嘉上
At least you didn't smash
你倒是没舍得
your model planes.
把你那些模型都砸了
For her?
为了她
It's not worth it.
不值得
Don't be angry.
别生气了
I've brought you some biscuits.
给你带了点饼干
Have a taste.
尝尝
I once read a medical journal.
我之前看过一本医学杂志
It says
上面说
if a man has some sweet food when he's angry,
人在生气的时候吃一些甜食
he'll soon calm down.
会快速让情绪稳定下来的
I've never heard about it before.
头一次听到这种说法
Try one.
尝一块
I didn't mean to quarrel with her.
我并不想和她吵架
She hates me.
她恨我
I complain about her.
我怨她
All because of my brother's death.
归根到底都是因为辛弟的死
But a dead man can't come back to life.
可人死不能复生
So, we can never be on good terms.
所以这个结永远也解不了
I know.
我知道
Sometimes when you're angry,
有时候心里憋着一口气
you won't feel good unless you give vent to your anger.
不发出来实在不舒服
You also quarrel with people?
先生也会和别人吵架
Of course.
当然会啦
After my family went broke,
我们家破产以后
we were often bullied.
没少受人欺负
I'm a woman
我一个女人
with old and sick parents.
带着又老又病的父母
If I were weak,
稍微软弱一点
I would have been greatly bullied
就会被这个世道欺负得
in such a cruel world.
连个渣子都不剩
I only witnessed how you reasoned things out.
只见过先生说大道理时候的样子
I can't imagine what you look like in a quarrel.
想不出你吵架是什么样
Actually,
其实
no one wants to quarrel.
谁都不愿意和别人起争执的
Ma'am lives a hard life, too.
太太也挺不容易的
Her son died.
儿子没了
Her husband is cold to her.
丈夫又对她很冷漠
She must be very lonely.
她自己也很孤寂痛苦的
But she can't leave like Sun Shaoqing.
但又不能像孙少清那样一走了之
Others can break out of this place,
别人可以挣脱
but she can't.
但她却不行
She's kind of poor.
也挺可怜的
I understand.
我知道了
I'll avoid arguing with her.
我以后避着她
She...
她
She just doesn't understand you.
只是不懂你
In my eyes,
在我看来
you're a loyal and righteous man.
你是一个有情有义的人
You protect your family
你会爱护家人
and shelter them from trouble.
用肩膀替他们遮风挡雨
In the future,
未来
no matter who marries you,
无论哪个女人嫁给你
she'll live a happy life.
都会很幸福的
Ma'am,
太太
what about Mr. Jiashang's birthday party?
大少爷的生日宴您看
Go tell Master
你去跟老爷说
that I don't feel well.
我身体不舒服 生病了
I'm aching all over and I can't think straight.
浑身痛得没办法思考
Don't bother me
没有什么重要的事情
unless you really have to.
就不要来烦我了
But Master said
可是老爷说
this is Mr. Jiashang's first time to
这是大少爷成年后
make an appearance in Shanghai since he became an adult.
第一次在上海亮相的生日
It has to be a grand party.
需要隆重举办
My head hurts.
我头痛啊
I can't speak. I need to rest.
不能说话 我要休息
Ma'am.
太太
For Jiashang's birthday party,
大哥的生日宴会
Father will invite many guests.
爹爹肯定会邀请很多客人来
How annoying!
烦死了
I don't even have a nice new dress.
我这一件能穿的新衣服都没有
Fanglin,
姐
you have a lot of dresses.
你不是有那么多衣服
Why do you still complain?
怎么还说没有衣服穿呀
Look at my hairstyle.
你看我这头发
It's the most popular French wave.
最流行的法式小卷
It's modern, isn't it?
时髦吧
Mm.
去年的衣服
isn't good enough for my new hairstyle.
怎么能配得上我今年的发型呢
As the saying goes,
正所谓
a girl always
女生的衣橱里
needs a new dress. Right?
永远都少那么一件衣服 对不对
- Miss Feng.
先生
Mother usually prepared
像往年这种大型的宴会
for such big parties in former years.
都是妈妈亲手操办的
But now she's having a problem with Jiashang.
但是这次妈妈和大哥闹了点矛盾
These days, she's in bed,
这几天都卧床不起
saying she's sick.
说是头疼脑热
Do you think
你们说
the birthday party
这生日宴
will be canceled?
该不会泡汤了吧
No way.
不会吧
It's Jiashang's 20th birthday party.
这可是大哥二十岁生日呢
Fanglin,
我倒觉得
Master may ask you
老爷有可能会把这次宴会
to hold the party, I guess.
交给芳林你来办
Seriously?
真的
Miss Feng,
冯先生
sorry to interrupt you.
打扰一下
Miss Fanglin,
大小姐
Master just asked you
老爷刚吩咐了
to take care of Mr. Jiashang's birthday party
下个月大少爷的生日宴
next month.
由您来办
Me?
我
Miss Feng,
冯先生
you're quite prophetic.
您果然料事如神
It's a great chance to exercise yourself.
这是一个极好的锻炼机会
Before,
你们俩之前
you held some tea parties, didn't you?
不是也主持过茶话会吗
At those tea parties,
以前的茶话会
we only invited a dozen classmates
不过是请十来个同学
to have fun at home.
到家里玩罢了
Yeah.
是啊
But this time,
像这次
Father will invite all the important men in Shanghai.
爹爹肯定会请遍整个上海滩的人
There will be at least
这 中外宾客算一起
one or two hundred Chinese and foreign guests.
少说也得有一两百人哪
Don't worry.
放心
Ma'am will help you.
太太是不会不管的
First, the residence should be cleaned.
公馆要先重新打扫一遍
Some of the furniture is broken
把那些平时损坏的
or has paint falling off.
褪色的
Replace some
你们该换新的换新的
and repaint some accordingly.
该给我补漆的补漆
Got it?
知道了吗
- Yes, Ma'am.
是 太太
The garden in front of the residence should be tended.
公馆前面的花园要重新修整一番
I won't let anyone
我绝对不能让旁人
laugh at our family.
看我们容家的笑话
Get to your business. Go.
散去吧 散去吧
- Yes.
是
Ms. Kang, keep a close eye on them.
康嫂 盯紧一点啊
Yes, Ma'am.
是 太太
Be quick. Get going.
都麻利点啊 快去快去
Thank you, Mother.
谢谢妈妈
It's so nice to have you around.
有你在真好
Sure.
那当然啦
I'll certainly make you
我一定让你成为全上海
the most graceful lady in Shanghai.
最体面的小姐
By the way, Mother,
对了 妈妈
I want Miss Feng to help me, too.
这次我想让冯先生也帮我
Miss Feng, you're very attentive.
冯先生做事倒是细心
Please help Fanglin
那这次就麻烦你
with the party.
帮一帮芳林
I'll reward you.
我不会亏待你啊
Don't worry, Ma'am.
太太请放心
If Miss Fanglin needs any help,
大小姐如果有任何需要帮忙的地方
I'll try my best.
我一定会尽力去做
- It counts on you. - Mm.
瞧你的啦
You must do your best
你一定把它做到最好
and show your father how capable you can be.
让你爹看看你多有本事
I know, Mother.
妈妈 我知道的
- I trust you. - Mm.
妈妈相信你
Miss.
小姐
Miss, have some soup.
小姐 您就喝一口吧
It's the snow clam and jujube soup
这可是容府
just delivered from Rong's Residence.
刚刚派人送来的雪蛤红枣汤
Master still cares for you.
想来老爷还是念着您的
When Master favored me,
想当年我受宠的时候
I had far better food than this.
有哪一日的吃食不比现在
I risked my life and gave birth to his son.
我拼了命地为他容定坤生下儿子
But I'm left alone in the hospital,
到头来却像一个破抹布一样
like a useless rag.
被扔在医院
How many times has he come to the hospital?
他来过医院几次
Has he ever visited me?
有哪一次是来看我的
Master is just angry.
老爷只是没消气罢了
When you get better
等咱们养好身子
and go back home with your son,
带着小少爷回了容府
you'll have the final say.
这一切还不都是您说了算
After Shaoqing ran away from home,
清儿这赌气一走
things got tough
孙家的日子
for our Sun family.
怎么可能好过
Do you really think the big fool at the door
你真当门口那傻大个
was sent by Master to protect us?
是老爷派来保护我们的
And Huang Shujun, the old hag.
还有黄淑君那个老妖婆
She won't let me override her again.
她怎么可能容我再骑到她头上去
I should be grateful that
不借机踩死我们孙家
she didn't take the opportunity to crash my family.
我就已经谢天谢地了
Come on in.
请进
Dr. Feng.
冯医生
Go tell your master
回去告诉你们家老爷
that in our hospital,
在我们医院
the adult and the baby are both lives
大人孩子都是命
and they will both be protected.
都得保
Miss Sun,
孙太太
how do you feel today?
今天感觉怎么样
Not bad.
还好
But you look pale.
这脸色看上去不太好啊
Have a blood test later.
一会儿啊 我们来验个血
If you feel anything wrong,
有什么问题的话
tell the nurse in time.
要及时跟护士说
Thank you, Dr. Feng.
多谢冯医生
You're weak
你体质不大好
and you need extra nutrition.
需要补充营养
The snow clam and jujube soup
这雪蛤红枣汤
is good for you.
对你挺好的
Have it when it's hot.
要趁热喝
Chuntao, give it to me.
春桃 快
All right, then.
行
Take a good rest.
那你先好好休息
I'll leave you alone.
我先出去了
See you, Dr. Feng.
冯医生慢走
Miss,
小姐
why are you flushing?
你脸怎么红了
Are you feeling unwell?
是不是哪里不舒服啊
Are you having a fever?
发烧了吗
- No. - Let me check.
没有
Exotic beasts.
奇珍异兽
Antiques and paintings.
古玩字画
Rare medicinal materials.
珍稀药材
And munitions, of course.
自然也包括军火
Come on. Be careful.
小心点
It'll explode if it falls.
这落地可炸啊
Be very careful.
小心点啊
Be careful.
慢点
You made it?
这是你自己做的
Yes. I made it.
对
Look. Here are more things.
来看看 后边还有呢
The price is negotiable.
价钱好商量
The quality isn't good.
这个质量不行
Take it easy.
别着急
Let's keep looking.
找找看
Have another look. Here are more things.
再看看 后边还有呢
- Thank you. - The price is negotiable.
多谢
Here are more things.
价钱好商量
Come back later.
一会儿再来啊
Come and have a look. Made in Germany.
来 老板 看一下 德国的
Boss,
老大
they've been walking around for a while,
我看他们在这儿绕了好几圈了
asking about munitions.
一直在打听军火的消息
They're apparently rich young men who haven't ever suffered.
一看就是没吃过苦的有钱少爷
The industry of munitions is so complicated.
我们军火这行水那么深
They're too inexperienced.
他们还嫩了点
This is a business coming to us.
这可是送上门的买卖
Will we do it?
咱做不做
Go talk to them.
你去会会他们
Hello, gentlemen.
两位
I hear you want some munitions.
听说要买点军火
Do you have the supply?
你有货
I certainly do.
货当然是有的
But I wonder
就是不知道两位
if you can pay the price.
要不要得起
Don't worry.
放心吧
As long as you can provide high-quality munitions,
只要货足够好
money isn't a problem.
钱不是问题
Check this out.
您看看这个
Made in Germany?
德国货
Right.
那是
We provide
我们家的货
the best goods in Shanghai.
全上海独一家
How many pieces do you have?
数量呢
You sound like
听您这口气
you want a big batch.
您这是要走批大的
Exactly.
当然
But where did you
不过你这批货
get the goods?
是何来路
You don't need to know that.
英雄莫问来路
It's the rule of the black market.
这是我们黑市的规矩
You pay and we give you the goods.
你们收货我们拿钱
When the deal is over,
钱货两清
we're done.
各不相干
If you have any concerns about it,
如果两位少爷还有什么顾虑的话
I can just
那我这单生意啊
call the deal off.
大可不干
We're in an emergency, aren't we?
现在不是救急吗
Where can we buy so many munitions?
哪儿能买那么多军火
Don't be too cautious.
你也别太谨慎了
Or we'll miss the chance.
最后错过了
What else do you have?
你们还有什么货
Small submachine gun and small grenades.
小冲锋枪 小手雷
We have all of them.
我们都有
I want to check the goods first.
我要先看货
How about this?
这样吧
If you really want to buy some,
如果两位诚心要买的话
let's set a date.
咱们约个时间
The night after tomorrow,
后天晚上
let's meet at the abandoned No.11 Cargo Terminal.
废弃的十一号仓库码头
What do you say?
怎么样
Deal.
可以
Fine.
好
See you there.
不见不散
- Fanglin. - Ah?
芳林
Come and have a look.
你来看一下
This is the guest list I've drafted.
这是我拟的所有宾客的名单
Check it.
你再对一下
I'll add some of Father's business friends.
这上面还要加一些爹爹生意上的宾客
- Check it carefully. - Mm.
仔细点啊
Look at this.
你看这个
I'll check it out with Xiucheng.
这个我要拿去跟秀成哥哥对一下
If guests avoid some certain food,
宾客对饭菜有忌讳的
write it down.
你都要标记出来
Don't just stare at Xiucheng
可不要光顾着看秀成哥哥
and ignore what he says.
忘了听他讲些什么
How annoying!
你太讨厌了
Don't say that. Don't.
你再说 你再说
Miss Fanglin, Miss Fanghua,
两位小姐
the hotel delivered many food samples.
酒店送来了好多试吃的产品
Right out there.
就在外面呢
Let's go.
走吧
- Miss Feng. - Miss Feng, join us.
冯先生 一起啊
All right.
好
Go.
走
This tastes good.
这个味道不错
Add it to the food list.
添到名单上去吧
Taste the red wine, please.
您再尝尝这个红酒
The red wine is perfect
这酒啊配这个炭烤小羊排
for grilled lamb chops.
再合适不过
Mm, I'll taste it later.
这个我一会儿试
Let me compare them.
我再对比一下
Mm.
先生
Come and taste it.
你也过来尝一下吧
All right.
好
So many kinds of dessert.
很多呀
I haven't tasted this kind yet. Try some for me.
这个还没有 您帮我尝尝
How does it taste?
怎么样
It tastes great.
这个特别好吃
This... This one tastes good, too.
这个 这个也不错
I'm sure
芳桦那个小馋猫
Fanghua will love it.
肯定喜欢吃这个
Jiashang.
大哥
Are you just back?
你这是刚回来吗
Yes.
对
What are you eating?
你们吃什么呢
We're picking the dessert.
我们在选甜品呢
This one tastes great.
这个好吃
Try some.
快尝尝
Why do I smell the sulfur?
怎么会有一股硫磺味儿